<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Courses on</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/</link><description>Recent content in Courses on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHM101A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/chm101a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/chm101a/</guid><description>This introductory laboratory course on chemistry to be done by all first year students.
Materials
Practical File (2013)
Practical File (2017)
Sample Report
Grading Key</description></item><item><title>CHM102A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/chm102a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/chm102a/</guid><description>This introductory course on chemistry to be done by all first year students.
The course content is divided into two parts. The first half consists of Organic Chemistry concepts, many of which are repititions of those that we studied during our JEE preparation. The second half consists of Physical Chemistry.
Books &amp;amp; Other References Physical Chemistry (by Peter Atkins)
2019-20-II
Quiz-1
Tutorials
Midsem</description></item><item><title>EE200A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee200a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee200a/</guid><description>This introductory course is the first core course to be done by all students under Electrical Engineering branch.
The course content is very straight-forward and easy. There are some conventions and definitions to be understood (not rememebered) and the most important and the only major topic is the Laplace Transform. Till Midsem, analog signals are covered while after midsem, digitals signals are taught but all concepts taught in the second half are almost same as the first half, the only difference being that they are applied on digital/discrete signals instead of analog signals.</description></item><item><title>EE210A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee210a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee210a/</guid><description>This course is a DC course, to be done in the 4th semester by the Electrical Engineering branch.
This course is the first course which will give you the feeling of what a specialisation in core electrical might look like. The course content includes discussions on diodes, BJTs and MOSFETs in the beginning, and then the complex structures, like amplifiers and output stages, are presented to you. Amplifier is the most element so make sure that you understand its properties.</description></item><item><title>EE250A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee250a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee250a/</guid><description>This course is a DC course, to be done in the 4th semester by the Electrical Engineering branch.
This course introduces you to a specific field of core electrical engineering, namely control systems, which have profound usgae in almost all controlled machinery like robotics. This course is somparatively easy than other core courses. Laplace transform, taught in EE200A - Signals, Systems and Networks, is the only mathematical tool used for almost all tasks in this course.</description></item><item><title>EE320A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee320a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee320a/</guid><description>This is a DC course to be done by all Electrial Engineering Students in the 5th semester.
The course content is somewhat a continuation of EE200A - Signals, Systems and Networks course. The fourier transform plays an important role in the representation of signals. A large part of the course focusses on different kinds of Modulation and their properties. These modulation techniques are later used to analyse and remove noise from a system.</description></item><item><title>EE330A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee330a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee330a/</guid><description>This is a DC course to be done by all Electrial Engineering Students in the 5th semester.
The course content is somewhat a continuation of ESO203A - Introduction to Electrical Engineering course. The first few lectures cover the basic circuit principles like Three Phase Systems and Per Unit analysis. Then the discussion advances to topics like Transmission Line paramteres and models. They are used to conduct Power Flow Analysis using self-consistent methods.</description></item><item><title>EE370A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee370a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee370a/</guid><description>This is a DC course to be done by all Electrial Engineering Students in the 5th semester.
The course content is a continuation of EE210A - Microelectronics I course, but focuses on the digital domain primarily. The first few lectures cover the basic electronics involving MOSFETs, using which the CMOS inverter is introduced. CMOS inverters are used to study Combinational Logic design. The logic gates are designed using CMOS and several other architectures.</description></item><item><title>EE653A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee653a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/ee653a/</guid><description>This course is a DE course offered by the Electrical Engineering department.
This course is similar to the EE250A - Control Systems Analysis course. The objective of this course is to introduce the students to basic concepts associated with control systems but in the digital domain and the methods of quantization and approximation to reduce error. This course lays a good foundation of digital control systems' analysis and helps the students interested in control systems inspired fields like robotics.</description></item><item><title>ESC101A</title><link>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/esc101a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iitk-resources.github.io/courses/esc101a/</guid><description>This course is a IC course, to be done in the 1st and 2nd semester by all students.
This course introduces you to basic programming in C.
Books &amp;amp; Other References Let us C (by Yashavant Kanetkar)
2019-20-II
Minor Quizzes
Major Quiz 1
Midsem</description></item></channel></rss>